# Muhammad Afandi Aziz

afandiaziz46@gmail.com | +62 857-7757-1810 | Bekasi, Indonesia | linkedin.com/in/afandiaziz github.com/afandiaziz

## **ABOUT ME**

Semester 6 student of Informatics Engineering at the Jakarta State Polytechnic who is easy to learn new things. I am proficient in website development with more than 5 years experience. I have both Front-End and Back-End skills and am interested in learning various fields. I have interests in Front-End, Back-End, DevOps.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Politeknik Negeri Jakarta,** BASc in Informatics Engineering *⊘* 2019 − Now

Depok, Indonesia

Kampus Merdeka Studi Independen Generasi GIGIH 2.0 by YABB & Gojek and

**Tokopedia,** Back End Engineer ∂

Feb 2022 – Now Jakarta, Indonesia

**SMK Negeri 2 Kota Bekasi,** Software Engineering *⊘* 2016 – 2019

Bekasi, Indonesia

# **PENGALAMAN KERJA**

# PT Dasa Windu Agung 🔗

Web Developer / Part-Time Nov 2017 – Aug 2019

Bekasi, Indonesia

Web Developer / Internship Jul 2017 – Nov 2017

Bekasi, Indonesia

#### ORGANIZATION AND VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

# Pengabdian Masyarakat Politeknik Negeri Jakarta di Dinas Kesehatan Kota

Depok, Back End Developer

2021 – 2022

Depok, Indonesia

- Designing the Tecodep Application (Telemedicine Covid-19 Depok City) from 0
- Integrating API into Depok Single Window application
- Served as Back End Developer of Tecodep Applications
- Create a chat system between patients and health workers
- Creating an application REST API
- Doing User Acceptance Testing

## **Competition of IT Festival (COMITFEST),** Head of the Web Design Competition

- Coordinator/chairman of the COMITFEST web design category for high school and equivalent

Oct 2018 – Nov 2018

Bekasi, Indonesia

- Create a web design contest rulebook, and coordinate members

# **SKILLS**

Laravel, Codeigniter, Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, NextJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, SQL, Ruby, JavaScript, PHP

## **CERTIFICATES AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

Competency Certificate - Full-Stack Website Developer, BuildWith Angga 2021

Certificate of Completion - Cloud Practitioner Essentials (AWS), Dicoding

Dec 2021 – Dec 2024

Certificate of Completion - Learn Basic Web Programming, Dicoding

May 2020 – May 2023

National Certification on Software Development by BNSP, Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi (BNSP)	Dec 2019 – Dec 2022
National Digital Talent Scholarship Program - Vocational School Graduate Academy (VSGA), Digital Talent Schoolarship Kementerian Komunikasi dan Informatika Republik Indonesia	2019
2nd place winner Student Competency Competition - Web Design, Kota Bekasi	2018
Finalist - Dinus Application Competition, Universitas Dian Nuswantoro (Semarang)	2018
1st place winner Web Design Competition, Universitas Trilogi (Jakarta)	2018
2nd place winner ASCO Web Design Festival, Universitas Mercu Buana (Bekasi)	2018
<b>Finalist - National IT Olympic (OTN) - Web Design,</b> Ministry of Education, Culture, Research, and Technology of the Republic of Indonesia	2017
3rd place winner Website & Wordpress Blog Competition, Universitas Mercu Buana (Bekasi)	2017
PROJECTS	
Inspirasi Dikti, Direktorat Jenderal Pendidikan Tinggi, Riset, dan Teknologi Kementerian Pendidikan, Kebudayaan, Riset, dan Teknologi   Web Developer / Freelance  - Merancang requirement aplikasi bersama stakeholder  - Merancang ulang konsep aplikasi dari 0  - Mengirim email secara otomatis saat user didaftarkan  - Membuat sistem assessment reformasi birokrasi dan zona integritas  - Mengintegrasikan API ke sistem Kemenpan dan Kemendikbud  - Melakukan user acceptance testing	Mar 2022 – Sekarang Jakarta, Indonesia
Sistem Informasi Kerja Sama, Politeknik Negeri Jakarta Web Developer / Freelance  - Merancang konsep aplikasi dari 0  - Membuat sistem informasi kerja sama Politeknik Negeri Jakarta  - Menampilkan data berupa grafik  - Membuat sistem pengajuan kerja sama	Feb 2022 – Mar 2022 Depok, Indonesia
<b>DirectHired</b> <i>⊗</i> Web Developer / Freelance	2021 – 2022 Singapore
<b>Tecodep (Telemedicine Covid-19 Depok City),</b> Dinas Kesehatan Kota Depok Back End Developer	2021 – 2022 Depok, Indonesia
<ul> <li>Disain.id</li> <li>Founder dan Front-End Developer</li> <li>- Membuat platform bagi para disainer, dan bertugas sebagai front-end developer menggunakan NextJS,</li> <li>- Menyusun strategi pembuatan aplikasi menggunakan metode scrum.</li> </ul>	2021 – 2022 Jakarta, Indonesia
<ul> <li>Aplikasi Decision Support System           Ø</li> <li>Web Developer         <ul> <li>Aplikasi sistem pendukung keputusan pembelian laptop</li> <li>Menggunakan metode TOPSIS</li> </ul> </li> </ul>	2021 Bekasi, Indonesia

<ul> <li>Expo TIK, Politeknik Negeri Jakarta  </li> <li>Web Developer / Freelance <ul> <li>Merancang requirement aplikasi bersama stakeholder</li> <li>Merancang konsep aplikasi dari 0</li> <li>Membuat sistem informasi expo/event pameran Jurusan Teknik Informatika dan Komputer, Politeknik Negeri Jakarta.</li> <li>Membuat sistem vote expo</li> <li>Membuat aplikasi hanya dalam 3 hari untuk event pameran</li> </ul> </li> </ul>	2021 Depok, Indonesia
<b>E-Commerce Puk Ami Ami</b> Web Developer / Freelance	2021 Probolinggo, Indonesia
<b>Upgrade Sistem Jurnal Politeknik Negeri Jakarta</b> <i>⊗</i> Software Engineer / Freelance	2021 Depok, Indonesia
Prosiding Politeknik Negeri Jakarta    Software Engineer / Freelance	2021 Depok, Indonesia
Company Profile Scenna Indonesia    Web Developer / Freelance	2020 Jakarta, Indonesia
Pasar Modal Syariah, Direktorat Pasar Modal Syariah	2020 Jakarta, Indonesia
<b>Point of Sale Inventory,</b> PT Graha Utama Timber	2020
Web Engineer / Freelance	Tangerang, Indonesia
Company Profile Mitra Beton Cor	2020
Web Developer / Freelance	Bekasi, Indonesia
Company Profile Warrior MMA HQ	2019
Web Developer / Freelance	Jakarta, Indonesia
<b>Aplikasi Praktek Kerja Lapangan,</b> SMK Negeri 2 Kota Bekasi	2019
Full-Stack Web Developer / Freelance	Bekasi, Indonesia
<b>Aplikasi Surat Jalan (PLTAM),</b> PT Dasa Windu Agung	2019
Web Developer / Part-Time	Bekasi, Indonesia
<b>Aplikasi Shipping Management (JIT),</b> PT Dasa Windu Agung	2019
Web Developer / Part-Time	Bekasi, Indonesia
<b>Aplikasi Rigid Foam,</b> PT Dasa Windu Agung	2019
Web Developer / Part-Time	Bekasi, Indonesia
MyNIK, PT Dasa Windu Agung	2018
Web Developer / Part-Time	Bekasi, Indonesia
<b>Web Angket Calon Lulusan &amp; Alumni,</b> SMK Negeri 2 Kota Bekasi <i>∂</i> Web Developer / Freelance	2018 Bekasi, Indonesia
<b>Web Bio Peserta Didik,</b> SMK Negeri 2 Kota Bekasi	2018
Web Developer / Freelance	Bekasi, Indonesia
<b>Aplikasi Exam,</b> SMK Negeri 2 Kota Bekasi	2018
Web Developer / Freelance	Bekasi, Indonesia
Company Profile PT Dasa Windu Agung ⊘ Web Developer / Part-Time	2018 Bekasi, Indonesia
<b>Web Bursa Kerja Khusus (BKK),</b> SMK Negeri 2 Kota Bekasi <i>⊘</i>	2017
Web Developer / Freelance	Bekasi, Indonesia

Recruitment System, PT Dasa Windu Agung 2017Web Developer / MagangBekasi, IndonesiaDWA Monitoring Web System (DMWS), PT Dasa Windu Agung2017Web Developer / MagangBekasi, Indonesia